if you've been on YouTube Anytime in the
past year you've probably noticed a lot
of videos trending talking about buying
boring businesses and how you can make
all sorts of money buy a simple HVAC
company or plumbing company or car wash
and once you get it operationalized
it'll basically run itself turn itself
into a cash cow but I'm here to tell you
the truth about this and at the end of
this video I will also touch on one of
the businesses that is an excellent buy
right now it can be purchased at a
reasonable price has excellent
financials great margins my name is
Sarah sharp I'm an attorney specializing
in mergers and AC positions and I've
been doing that for over a decade I also
help people buy and exit businesses and
I am the founder of deal Academy but
more on that later but before we get
started I want to clarify something
because I am in no way trying to talk
you out of buying these types of
businesses they are all excellent
businesses to buy but when someone
presents them as trouble-free Recession
Proof businesses that run themselves
while you're on your yacht in the
Mediterranean with collecting checks
passively I do have a problem with that
because I talk to business owners every
day exiting these types of businesses
and I will share the feedback that they
give me as to why they're selling the
truth may surprise you the truth is that
these businesses are like any other
business which means they're filled with
problems and they are pain in the ass to
run they have problems with cash flow
payroll collections problems problems
with employees Staffing and 80% of the
business owners I talked to are exiting
because they've been doing it a handful
of years and are burnt out and wanting
to sell I've talked to buyers on the
side that approach me to help them
acquire an HVAC company or other
businesses with this preconceived notion
that they're going to be able to ramp up
marketing and passively manage it after
they acquire it with zero experience in
HVAC or Home Services space and think
they're going to be successful the truth
is that these types of businesses are
very people intensive which means you
have to create a company and a culture
and when you do that you have people
which means you're going to inevitably
have problems have to create Management
systems and in order for that to run
effectively so if you're thinking you
can buy a business right off into the
sunset with your Millions I urge you to
reconsider because that is not the
reality that I see or hear from business
owners I talk to every single day so
first off let's talk about why these
businesses are not just passively
managed cash cows that they are cracked
up to be in any example I'm going to
refer to I'm going to speak about
haacker Plumbing or any other home
service business these are things like
pool cleaners or landscapers or anything
that involves a person going into a
customer's home the biggest issue with
these businesses is that they all
require substantial overhead in the form
of employees which creates moving pieces
in the need for management andem if
you're going to have people calling in
sick requesting time off people means
you're going to be paying for health
insurance workman's compensation general
liability short-term long-term
disability life insurance 401ks not to
mention you'll be constantly dealing
with people asking for raises or feeling
like they're underappreciated Meanwhile
your margins get rated and you have to
scale which forces price raises which
then requires you to remain competitive
on the market in the case of businesses
like car washes you need to have people
that are maintaining equipment filling
up the soap dispensers cleaning up trash
dealing with customer service complaints
because you will have issues customer
service is at the Forefront of every
business since people are the ones
handing over their hard-earned dollars
to wash their vehicles unfortunately
there's not an easy way out of these
types of businesses so if you're
thinking this is an easy and simple to
manage business you should strongly
reconsider because these are very
complex businesses and businesses that
require a lot of specialized licensing
that can take years to acquire that's
why a lot of businesses I represent on
the buyer acquisition side that are
effective are have operating businesses
they've created operationalized
companies they're basically professional
management companies to manage the
businesses they are acquiring they have
entire executive staff overseeing all
aspects of marketing and accounting all
the way down to customer service and
Human Resources these companies are
professional managers and they know what
it takes to run and then operationalize
a business which is why they're
successful in competing the marketplaces
but if you think you're just going to
buy one of these companies as a small
individual and be prepared to take on
all of the problems of an acquisition
when you buy you might be surpris not to
mention that any business employees are
a little shaken up at first after an
acquisition and nervous of what new
owners are going to do are they going to
fire everyone are they going to cut
everyone's pay and benefits there's a
lot of unknown acquisition and you can
be dealing with Mutiny overnight after
acquiring a business you might have to
float it for several months or years
while you restabilize operations which
is okay if you're a professional
management company obviously you
probably don't have to have this fear
because human executive team behind you
supporting you on the r operation side
so this probably doesn't apply to you
for a one man or a one woman show trying
to buy a company these are all things
you want to consider beforehand and be
ready to buy off before you take the
plch and sign on the dotted SBA loan
line now if operating and managing a
company doesn't scare you then by all
means take the plunge and for more
information on how you can work with
this there'll be a few links in the
description below where we can help you
with merges and Acquisitions as well as
with deal Academy of course which I'll
talk about but before we touch on that
if you've enjoyed this content so far
please make sure you smash and like that
button for the algorithm and consider
subscribing to my channel if you haven't
done so already we put out weekly
content on mergers and Acquisitions
buying and selling businesses and how to
acquire accounting practices which is
one of the best kept secrets in the
business world right now so if you're
interested in this type of content
subscribing is a great way that you can
support the channel and also stay up to
date with an actual licens attorney
mergers and acquisition specialist that
specializes on this topic and is doing
deals every single day the reason we are
very active in the mergers and
acquisition space and with all
businesses right now not just accounting
practices is because there's such a high
interest rate a lot of the money that
was going into real estate as an
investment has shifted away from the
market because of residential real
estate and real estate in general isn't
as profitable to cash flow if there's
any debt on the property because market
prices haven't adjusted yet as a result
you can get a much better Roi through
the acquisition of a business which is
why investors have shifted their focus
to Acquisitions driving up the activity
in a lot of the business sector in a
nutshell the reason we help people buy
and sell a lot of accounting practices
is one they have excellent financials
and clean books which makes sense
because they're accounting practice two
limited licensing requirements if
there's a firm limited to bookkeeping
and no enacting in CBA a test work
capacity and three the most exciting
they have excellent margins sometimes
40% and a very reasonable multiple they
trade out so we'll do a deep dive on
this type of business in another video
and we'll make an entire course on this
topic at deal Academy that will be able
to teach you to identify the best type
of practice to buy how to avoid common
mistakes most people make when buying
and selling these businesses and how to
inspect financials and operations before
going under contract to ensure you're
targeting the right business so that
your acquisition turns into a profitable
money making Venture and you don't end
up Buy buy inip as mentioned earlier
there is a video popping up on the
screen now that does a deep dive on the
topic of accounting practices and why we
have so many people entering this space
to buy this business so before you check
that out let me know what you think in
the comment section below and what
business questions you have I'm always
curious what projects people are working
on and the questions they have we
created this channel to be a resource
for entrepreneurs so make sure you post
your comments and questions below